Register of the Valerian Ivanovich Moravskii Papers, 1917-1937.
Hoover Institution Archives
- Relations with China, Czechoslovakia and Japan, 1921-1936
  - Japan
    - Miscellaneous material in Japanese. Includes documents and reports (Folder 40)
    - Printed Matter
      - Translations from Japanese
        - Hayashi, Kenjiro. Interview with The Christian Science Monitor, July 1936 (Folder 41)
        - Okatsu, T., "Mir vsekh narodov mira i Sibir'," n.d. (Folder 42)
        - Okuma, "Chto neobkhodimo dlia zaokeanskogo razvitiia Iaponii," n.d. (Folder 43)
        - Tanaka, Kunisige. Interview with The Christian Science Monitor, July 1936 (Folder 44)
        - "Copy of a Note Addressed By the Japanese Minister to China to the Acting Minister For Foreign Affairs of the Nanking Government" Japanese Legation in China, Nov. 1931 (Folder 45)
      - "Politika Iaponii v Manchzhurii i Mongolii". Memorandum of the Prime Minister presented to the Emperor of Japan, n.d. (Folder 46)
      - Japanese newspapers
        - The Japan Times and Mail, Jan, 23, 1933 (Folder 47)
        - The Osaka Mainichi, Aug. 10, 1922 (Folder 48)
        - Miscellaneous newspapers (Folder 49)
        - Congress of Oppressed Peoples, bulletin (Folder 50)
        - Mokvekvai Society, newspaper
    - Reports. n.d.
      - "K polozheniiu v KHarbine" (Folder 51)
      - "Polozhenie v Iaponii"
      - "Puti iaponskoi politiki na 1935 god"
      - "Sovremennaiia Iaponiia"
      - "Vnutrennee polozhenie Iaponii stanovitsia ugrozhaiushchim"
      - Report re situation in the Far East, 1934 (Folder 52)
      - A.V., "Vooruzhennoe stolknovenie Ameriki i IAponii," n.d. (Folder 53)
      - Chertkov, G.I. (Folder 54)
        - "Mnenie iaponskikh kommersantov o iapono-sovetskoi torgovle," Dec. 1926
        - "Sev. Manchzhuriia-kliuch' k razvitiiu russko- iaponskoi torgovli," n.d.
      - Chertkov, G.I. and Orginskii, G. Miscellaneous short reports. Includes reports on Japanese- American and Japanese-Soviet relations, Nov. 1934-Jan. 1935 (Folder 55)
      - Orginskii, G.
        - "IAponskaia periodicheskaia pressa, eia osobennosti i eia tendentsii," Apr.1934 (Folder 56)
        - "V godovshchinu smerti Sigemaru Sugiyama," July 1936 (Folder 57)
    - Treaties
      - "Dogovor S.U.O.A.S. i chlenov Nizhnei Palaty Iaponskoi Imperii o vzaimnom sodeistvii," March 1925 (Folder 58)
      - Legal agreement. D.L. KHorvat, V.I. Moravskii and G.G. Gondo, Kamimura, July 1928 (Folder 59)
      - Negotiations of C.P.P.O.A.S. with Japanese Military Agent Gen. Suzuki re joint expedition to Chinese Turkestan. Miscellaneous material, Aug. 1934 (Folder 60)
      - Short report re history of negotiations with the Japanese, 1932 (Folder 61)
    - Correspondence
      - Council of Plenipotentiaries of Siberian Organizations (Folder 62)
        - Greeting to unknown correspondent, 1933
      - KHorvat, D.L. (Folder 63)
        - Shin-To A, Nov.-Dec. 1929
      - Kishi, Yaziro (Folder 64)
        - Chan Fan-sian, (re V.I. Moravskii), May 1929
      - Levchatkin-Atkins, S.V. (Folder 65)
        - Okatsu, Feb. 1933
      - Moravskii, V.I.
        - Inukai, (Prime Minister of Japan), Sept. 1930 (Folder 66)
      - Kudo, Kentsutaro, March 1933 (Folder 67)
        - Taga, Muneiki, Aug. 1932-March 1933 (Folder 68)
        - Tanabe, March 1933 (Folder 69)
        - Tanaka, Zenritsu, March 1933 (Folder 70)
      - Niisuma, Jiro (Folder 71)
        - Levchatkin-Atkins, S.V., Feb. 1933
      - Okatsu (Folder 72)
        - V.I. Moravskii, (includes telegrams in Japanese), Jan.-May 1933
      - Taga, Muneiki (Folder 73)
        - Moravskii, V.I., Sept. 1928-May 1932
      - Tokuchika, Miki (Folder 74)
        - Moravskii, V.I., April 1933
      - Torii, T.
        - Chertkov, G.I., Sept.-Nov. 1928 (Folder 75)
        - Levchatkin-Atkins, S.V., June 1932 (Folder 76)
        - Moravskii, V.I., Sept. 1928-May 1932 (Folder 77)
      - Shin-To-A (Folder 78)
        - Moravskii, V.I., Aug. 1929
- Commercial Enterprises and Banking, 1915-1933
  Reports on the economic situation in the Far East; contracts and agreements to establish commercial enterprises and miscellaneous material re Russian banks in the Far East. Includes material on Mongolia. Arranged by topic.
  - General. Reports (Box 5)
    - Cherednichenko, V.P., confidential reports to V.I. Moravskii, Dec. 1928 (Folder l)
    - Okulich, K., "Ob organizatsii Sibirskago Gosudarstvenago Banka," 1918 (Folder 2)
    - Zlatoustovskii, A.A., "O finansovo-economicheskoi avtonomii okrain," 1922
    - Report re Russian enterprises in China, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Commercial Enterprises
    - Exploitation of timber, Eastern Siberia
      - Draft of laws governing the exploitation of timber in European Russia and Siberia, n.d. (Folder 4)
      - Contract, D.K. Naryshkin and V.P. Cherednichenko, 1915 (Folder 5)
      - Report, K.F. Vil'chinskii, 1918 (Folder 6)
      - Instruction of the Minister of Agriculture re exploitation of timber, March 1919 (Folder 7)
    - Tsentrsoiuz, (meat supply for Mongolia, Manchuria and the Trans-Baikal Region). Miscellaneous material, 1920-1921 (Folder 8)
    - C.P.R.O.A.S. Draft of project for establishing fur trading station on the Shantrak Islands, Aug. 1922 (Folder 9)
    - China-American Shoe Co. Contract, Sept. 1923 (Folder 10)
    - Commercial-Industrial and Financial Concern. Draft of contract and miscellaneous material, July 1932 (Folder 11)
    - Zaitsev, Gen. I.M., miscellaneous commercial projects, Aug. 1923 (Folder 12)
  - Concessions
    - Mongolia
      - French Commercial Bank of Mongolia. Statutes, July 1922 (Folder 13)
      - Contract, A.V. Balakin, (representing Mongol princes) and Edmond Sterpen re commercial exploitation of Mongolia. Includes drafts, final copy and French translation, Apr.-May 1925 (Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, Balakin, A.N., correspondence with E. Sterpen and V.I. Moravskii, May 1925 (Folder 15)
      - Power of attorney, A.V. Balakin to V.I. Moravskii, March 1925 (Folder 16)
      - Promissory note, A.N. Balakin to V.I. Moravskii, May 1925 (Folder l7)
      - Reports
        - "Bogatstvo Manchurii i Vnutrennei Mongolii," n.d. (Folder l8)
        - Miscellaneous, Feb.-March 1935 (Folder 19)
    - Okhotsk Railroad. Draft of agreement to build, n.d. (Folder 20)
    - Suchansk coal fields. Draft of concession to exploit, n.d.
  - Banking
    - All-Russian Peasant Union Bank. Protocol of meeting, Oct. 1921 (Folder 21)
    - Russian-American Joint Stock and Credit Society. Letter from V.I. Moravskii, May 1931 (Folder 22)
    - Russo-Asiatic Bank. Miscellaneous material re its liquidation, 1932-1933 (Folder 23)
- Russian Gold and Monies Deposited Abroad, 1920-1936
  Material re attempts by the Council of Plenipotentiary Representatives of the Organizations of Autonomous Siberia and its representatives to recover monies, gold and supplies of the Imperial and Provisional Governments deposited abroad or confiscated by Chinese and Japanese authorities. Includes documents and correspondence dealing with the so-called Kolchak gold and the Podtiagin and Miller Affairs. Arranged by topic.
  - General (Box 5)
    - Correspondence with lawyers and law firms
      - C.P.R.O.A.S.
        - IAvdynskii, IU.A., Jan. 1925-July 1927 (Folder 24)
        - Du Pac de Marsoulies, A., Dec. 1925-Jan. 1928 (Folder 25)
        - Suzuki, Shun, Sept. 1923-July 1932 (Folder 26)
      - IAvdynskii, IU.A.
        - Miscellaneous, mostly undated correspondence (Folder 27)
        - Moravskii, V.I., Jan. 1925-July 1932 (Folder 28)
      - Du Pac de Marsoulies, A.
        - Miscellaneous correspondence, Apr. 1926-May 1928. (Includes letter from G.M. Semenov) (Folder 29)
      - Suzuki, Shun
        - Moravskii, V.I., June 1931-Sept. 1936 (Folder 30)
        - Miscellaneous letters and notes, n.d. (Folder 31)
        - Miscellaneous correspondence re Shun Suzuki, Feb. 1920-Apr.1925 (Folder 32)
    - Contracts and legal agreements with lawyers and law firms
      - C.P.R.O.A.S. and Shun Suzuki, Feb. 1922-Feb. 1926 (Folder 33)
      - Marsoulies, du Pac de, powers of attorney, March 1927 (Folder 34)
      - P.P. Petrov, G.A. Ver'ibitskii and Shun Suzuki, June 1932 (Folder 35)
      - Slavianskii, K.I., (Russian Farmer's Union) and Shun Suzuki, July 1932
      - Slavianskii, K.I., (Russian Farmer's Union) and V.I. Moravskii, March 1932 (Folder 36)
      - Shun Suzuki, promissory note to V.N. Shchekin, Sept. 1922 (Folder 37)
    - List of foreign banks holding Russian government deposits, n.d. (Folder 38)
    - Printed material. Pogrebetskii, A.I., "Sud'ba zolota deponirovannogo zagranitsu pravitel'stvom Admirala Kolchaka". [Typescript chapter from Pogrebetskii, A.I., Denezhnoe Obrashchenie i Denezhnye Znaki Dal'nego Vostoka za Period Voiny i Revoliutsii, (1914-1924), "Knizhnoe Delo," Harbin, 1924] (Folder 39)
  - Bank deposits
    - Hong-Kong Shanghai Bank
      - Correspondence
        - Beytagh, L.M. Letters to K.K. Grosbois, June 1926 (Folder 40)
        - Deacons, Solicitors and Notaries. Letters to IU. A. IAdvinskii, March 1931-Jan. 1935 (Folder 41)
        - KHorvath, D.L. Letter to Johns, Solicitors, Dec. 1928 (Folder 42)
        - Moravskii, V.I.
          - Chertkov, G.I., Oct. 1923 (Folder 43)
          - Director, Hong-Kong Shanghai Bank, Oct. 1927 (Folder 44)
      - Miscellaneous material of C.P.R.O.A.S. Includes drafts of reports, memoranda and powers of attorney, n.d. (Folder 45)
    - Russo-Asiatic Bank
      - List of deposits in the bank, n.d. (Folder 46)
      - Miller Affair (Folder 47)
        - Power of attorney from C.P.P.O.A.S. to V.I. Moravskii, Sept. 1923
        - Testimony, G.I. Chertkov, Yokohama District Court, Aug. 1925
        - Letter of Ataman G. Semenov to Shun Suzuki, n.d.
  - Realization of government monies in foreign banks
    - Contracts, C.P.R.O.A.S.
      - Chungtao T. Chu, Apr. 1925 (Box 6, Folder l)
      - Drysdale, Roberts and Co. Draft, n.d. (Folder 2)
      - Dulevskii, S.IU. Draft, n.d. (Folder 3)
      - Orin de Motte Walker and Co., (includes power of attorney), n.d. (Folder 4)
      - Rodger, N.D. and Co., Sept. 1936 (Folder 5)
    - Powers of attorney and letters of instruction, C.P.R.O.A.S.
      - Grosbois, K.K., (includes other correspondence with K.K. Grosbois), Aug. 1926-Nov. 1927 (Folder 6)
      - Moravskii, V.I., Feb. 1922-Feb. 1925 (Folder 7)
  - Podtiagin Affair
    - Legal documents. Arranged chronologically
      - Decision, Tokyo District Court, case of Kuroki Sinke and Shun Suzuki vs. M.P. Podtiagin, March 1925 (Folder 8)
      - C.P.R.O.A.S. report re Podtiagin case, Nov. 1925 (Folder 9)
      - Testimony, Mori Takekuma and G.M. Semenov, Tokyo District Court of Appeals, Feb. 1926 (Folder 10)
      - Deposition, A.A. Balakin, Tokyo District Court of Appeals, May 1926 (Folder 11)
      - Instigation of legal proceedings
        - C.P.P.O.A.S. vs G.M. Semenov, Kuroki Sinke and Shun Suzuki, n.d. (Folder 12)
        - Chertkov, G.I vs Kisi Seichi and Kuroki Sinke, n.d. (Folder 13)
      - Order for payment, Kitsuki District Court, Sept 1927 (Folder 14)
      - Contract, D.L. Khorvat, V.I. Moravskii and Kondo,(re realization of money awarded to G.M. Semenov by Kitsuki District Court), July 1928 (Folder 15)
    - Correspondence
      - Chertkov, G.I.
        - Manabe, A.P., July 1928 (Folder 16)
        - Kisi Seichi, Oct. 1929 (Folder 17)
        - Procurator, Tokyo District Court, Oct. 1929
        - Yokohama Specie Bank, Oct. 1929
      - Chiga
        - Moravskii, V.I., (telegrams), July-Aug. 1928 (Folder 18)
        - KHorvat, D.L.,(telegrams signed Chiga, Kamemura, Chertkov), Aug. 1928 (Folder 19)
      - Fukuda Gumi Co. (Folder 20)
        - Petrov, P.P., Jan. 1921
      - Kamchatka Regional Committee (Folder 21)
        - Moravskii,V.I., Sept. 1929
      - Manabe, A.P.
        - Chertkov, G.I., Feb. 1926- Nov. 1928 (Folder 22)
        - Moravskii, V.I., March 1932 (Folder 23)
      - Moravskii, V.I.
        - Igo, (Japanese Minister of the Interior), Nov. 1927 (Folder 24)
      - KHorvat, D.L., (includes draft of agreement with Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaievich ), Nov. 1926- Nov. 1927 (Folder 25)
      - Yokohama Specie Bank and Banque Belge Pour L'Etranger, Aug.-Sept. 1928 (Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re disposition of Podtiagin money, June-Sept. 1928 (Folder 27)
    - Powers of attorney
      - Semenov, G.M. to V.N. Shchekin, Feb. 1922 (Folder 28)
      - Moravskii, V.I. to E. Sterpen, Dec. 1925 (Folder 29)
    - Printed matter. Translations from Japanese newspapers (Folder 30)
      - Dzi-Dzi, Sept. 12, 1929
      - Tokyo Asakhi Shimbun, May-Sept. 1929
  - Kolchak gold. Arranged chronologically
    - Certificate from Col. Suga re receipt of gold, typescript copy, Feb. 1920 (Folder 31)
    - Receipt from Col. Isome (head of Japanese War Mission in Manchuria) to Maj. Gen. P.P.Petrov (Head of Supply of Far Eastern Army) for gold deposited with the Japanese, typescript copy, Nov. 1920 (Folder 32)
    - Memoranda and reports
      - Kalmykov, Ataman, May, 1920 (Folder 33)
      - Maj. Gen. P.P. Petrov, June 1923 (Folder 34)
      - Miscellaneous, 1922-1928 (Folder 35)
    - Letter of guarantee, Ryohei Uchida and T. Usa to C.P.R.O.A.S., March 1923 (Folder 36)
    - Powers of attorney
      - Semenov, G.M. to A.V. Balakin, Feb. 1922 (Folder 37)
      - C.P.P.O.A.S. to V.I. Moravskii, Aug. 1923- Feb. 1925 (Folder 38)
    - Certificate transferring Suga receipt from G.M. Semenov to A.V. Balakin, typescript copy, Feb. 1922 (Folder 39)
    - Printed matter, KHarbinskie Ezhednevnyia Novosti, Sept. 17,1932. (Typescript excerpt) (Folder 40)
  - Gold coin confiscated by Chinese customs, March 1920
    - Correspondence
      - Army of the Far East and the Mende-Armstrong Co. Feb. 1920- Oct. 1932 (Folder 41)
      - C.P.R.O.A.S. (Folder 42)
        - Chang Tso-lin, Marshal, Apr. 1926
    - Contract, V.I. Moravskii and V.P. Cherednichenko-Mersie, 1924 (Folder 43)
    - Powers of attorney, C.P.R.O.A.S. and V.I. Moravskii, Feb. 1925 (Folder 44)
    - Report, anonymous, n.d. (Folder 45)
  - Port Arthur gold
    - Correspondence (Folder 46)
      - Anonymous, letter to A.N. Lipovitskii, n.d.
      - Japanese Imperial Consulate Tientsin, letter to T. Okatsu and A.A. Lernet, n.d.
      - Lernet, A.A., letter to V.I. Moravskii, June 1933
      - Lipovitskii, A.N., letters to A.A. Lernet and T. Okatsu, June 1933
      - Okatsu, T., letter to A.N. Lipovitskii, n.d.
    - Printed matter, The Japan Times, Tokyo, Oct. 5, 1936. (Typescript excerpt) (Folder 47)
- Emigre Organizations in the Far East, 1921-1933
  Correspondence, publications, proclamations, protocols of meetings and resolutions of Russian emigre political and social organizations in the Far East. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Bratstvo Russkoi Pravdy. Letter from head of the Maritime Section of the B.R.P. to head of the North Eastern Autonomous B.R.P., 1934 (Box l., Folder 48)
  - Dal'nevostochnyi Komitet Aktivnoi Zashchity Rodiny. Excerpt from resolution, March 1927 (Folder 49)
  - Dal'nevostochnyi Musul'manskii Natsional'nyi Komitet. Statutes, n.d. (Folder 50)
  - Dal'nevostochnoe Soveshchanie Ob'edinennoi Emigratsii. Excerpt from resolution, n.d. (Folder 51)
  - Kamchatskii Oblastnoi Komitet. Includes short history, resolutions, reports, correspondence, Sept. 1918-Dec. 1938 (Folder 52)
  - Komitet Deistviia (Folder 53)
    - Memorandum, n.d.
    - Protocol, June 1927
  - Komitet Idel'-Urala Tiurko Tatar Goroda Shankhaia. "Nash Otvet," protest leaflet, n.d. (Folder 54)
  - Komitet Zashchity Prav i Interesov Russkikh v Shankhae. Ustav, Shanghai, 1927 (Folder 55)
  - Konstitutionnaia Oboronitel'naia Liga (Constitutional Defense League) (Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, July 1926-June 1927
    - Report of activities, May 1926
    - Statutes. Draft, n.d.
  - Manchzhurskii Ekonomicheskii Soiuz. Usta v, Apr. 1924 (Folder 57)
  - Obshchestvo Sibiriakov (Folder 58)
    - IAkushev, I.A., chairman, Obshchestvo Sibiriakov Ch.S.R., letter to Nasha Gazeta, March 1933
    - Shankhaiskaia Zaria. Clipping, n.d.
  - Obshchestvo Vozsozdaniia Rossii. Statutes, 1929 (Folder 59)
  - Predstaviteli Kooperativnykh Organizatsii. Protocol of meeting, Oct. 1921 (Folder 60)
  - Raboche-Krestiansko-Kazach'a Oppozitsiia Russkikh Fashystov (Folder 61)
    - Deklaratsiia, Nov. 1927
    - Kratkaia Programma, 1927
    - Vestnik, No. l, Oct. 1928
  - Rossiiskaia Natsional-Sotsialisticheskaia Partiia. Program, n.d. (Folder 62)
  - Rossiisko Natsional'no Trudovaia Partiia. Leaflets (Folder 63)
    - "Instruktsiia," Oct. 1932
    - "K voprosu o finansovom plane," Oct. 1932
  - Russkaia Fashistskaia Partiia (Folder 64)
    - Letter of V.I. Moravskii to Gen. V. Kozmin, n.d.
    - Copy of leaflet against Nasha Gazeta, 1933
    - Resolution, Minister of Internal Affairs, (China), Jan. 1935. Russian translation.
  - Russkaia Natsional'naia Obshchina v Shankhae. Statutes. n.d. (Folder 65)
  - Russkii Krestiansko-Kazachii Soiuz v Manchzhurii i Mongolii. Statutes, n.d. (Folder 66)
  - Russkii Natsional'nyii Sovet. Resolution, n.d. (Folder 67)
  - Russkii Tsentr. "Obrashchenie k russkim prozhyvaiushchim za-granitsei," Dec. 1931 (Folder 68)
  - Russkoe Demokraticheskoe Ob'edinenie. "Prizyv k sozdaniiu demokraticheskago ob'edineniia". Leaflet, n.d. (Folder 69)
  - Russkoe Obshchestvo v Manchzhurii i Mongolii (Folder 70)
    - Memorandum to new members, n.d.
    - Resolutions, n.d.
    - Slavianskii, K.I., speech, March 1932
  - Russkoe Natsional'noe Obshchestvo v Iaponii (Folder 71)
    - Open letter from the committee, March 1931
    - Protocol of meeting, July 1930
  - Sibirskii Ispolnitel'nyi Komitet po Bor'be s Kommunizmom. Resolution. Draft, 1923 (Box 7, Folder l)
  - Sibirskii Krestianskii Soiuz. Statutes, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Sibirskii Krug (Folder 3)
    - Resolution No. 2, Oct. 1932
    - Statutes, n.d.
  - Soiuz Russkikh Gosudarstvennykh Liudei (Folder 4)
    - "IUbileinoe soveshchanie," Oct. 1927
    - "Otvet g. P. Krupenskomu," n.d.
  - Soiuz Sibiriakov Oblastnikov Federalistov. "Programma," 1922 (Folder 5)
  - Trudovaia Krestianskaia Partiia, Krestianskaia Rossiia (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. Miscellaneous, 1931-1934
    - Pamphlets
      - Chto krestianin poluchaet za svoi khleb? 1927
      - Kak kommunisticheskaia vlast' boretsia s krestianstvom, 1928
      - Kak zhivet rabochii v svobodnoi strane, 1928
      - "Krestianskaia Rossiia," Trudovaia Krestianskaia Partiia, 1928
    - Vasilevskii, K., "IAponiia i Rossiia," Znamia Rossii, No. 2, Praga, 1934
  - Verkhovnyii Narodnyii Sovet Sibiri. Resolution, Apr. 1929 (Folder 7)
  - Vozrozhdenie. "Tem kto ponimaet". Open letter, 1921 (Folder 8)
  - Vsesibirskii Komitet Deistviia (Folder 9)
    - Protocol of meeting, Apr. 1927
    - Letter to G.I. Chertkov, Oct. 1927
  - Vseslavianskaia Liga v Manchzhu go. Memorandum, 1933 (Folder 10)
  - Vysshyii Monarkhicheskii Sovet, No. 52. Aug. 27, 1922 (Folder 11)
  - Zabaikal'skoe Stanichnoe Pravlenie. Miscellaneous material and correspondence of V.G. Kazakov, Sept. 1925-Nov. 1929 (Folder 12)
  - Zakonoposlushno-Monarkhicheskoe Dvizhenie (Folder 13)
    - "Chego zhdat' ot vozstanovleniia zakonnoi monarkhii v Rossii," Izdanie Tsentra Zakonoposlushnykh v Ch.S.R., Praga, 1925
    - "Chto dast Rossii vozstanovlenie zakonnoi monarkhii," n.d.
  - Miscellaneous monarchist material. Includes "Legitimist" proclamations and correspondence, 1926-1930 (Folder 14)
  - Printed matter. Proclamations and leaflets of miscellaneous political groups and organizations
    - Undated (Folder 15)
    - May 1925-1933 (Folder 16)
- Subject File, 1918-1933
  Includes correspondence of the Russian emigre community of the Far East with the League of Nations and reports and miscellaneous material re railroads in China and Manchuria. Arranged by topic.
  - Miscellany (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Le Echo de la Chine, Shanghai. Excerpts, March 1926 (Folder 18)
  - League of Nations. Correspondence
    - C.P.R.O.A.S. (Folder 19)
      - General Secretary of the League of Nations, June 1931
      - Chairman, Nansen International Refugee Office, July 1932
      - Keno, G.G., representative of the Nansen International Refugee Office, July 1932
    - Kalinin, N.V., letter to G.G. Keno, representative of the Nansen International Refugee Office, July 1932 (Folder 20)
    - Malinovskii, N.P., letter to the chairman of the International Labor Bureau of the League of Nations, Feb. 1927 (Folder 21)
    - Russkoe Obshchestvo v Manchzhurii i Mongolii, "Doklad Vysokoi Obsledovatel'noi Komissii Ligi Natsei," n.d. (Folder 22)
  - Railroads
    - Fletcher, H.P., "Proposal for the Neutralization of Railways in Manchuria," 1909 (Folder 23)
    - Kataev, V., reports to C.P.R.O.A.S., 1933 (Folder 24)
    - Orginskii, G., report re on Japanese-Soviet negotiations re Manchurian railroad, Jan. 1925 (Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous material re Far Eastern Railroad. Includes printed material, correspondence and reports, 1918-1933 (Folder 26)
    - Short report re prospects of railroad building in China, n.d. (Folder 27)
  - Rasputin, Grigorii, letter to Nicholas II, (copy), n.d. (Folder 28)
  - Russian Gymnasium in Harbin, projected expenditures, n.d. (Folder 29)
- Correspondence., 1921-1937.
  Miscellaneous correspondence of members and affiliates of the Council of Plenipotentiary Representatives of the Organizations of Autonomous Siberia. Includes correspondence of G.I. Chertkov, V.I. Moravskii, M.P. Golovachev and A.V. Sazonov. Arranged alphabetically by author with correspondents listed below in alphabetical order.
  - Miscellaneous mostly undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Japanese, unidentified (Folder 31)
  - Agapov, E.M.
    - Moravskii, V.I., May 1922-Dec. 1937 (Folder 32)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Nov. 1922-May 1925 (Folder 33)
  - A.K.
    - Sazonov, V.I.,June 1921 (Folder 34)
  - Altaev and Gross (Folder 35)
    - Chertkov, G.I., n.d.
    - Golovachev, M.P., n.d.
    - Moravskii, V.I., June 1927-March 1928
  - Anadenkov, P.S. (Folder 36)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Apr. 1928
  - Andogskii, A.I. (Folder 37)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Apr.-June 1923
  - Anthony, Archbishop of Kiev and Galich (Folder 38)
    - Rerikh, N.K., Oct.-Nov. 1934
  - Balakin, A.V.
    - Moravskii, V.I., Aug. 1923-Sept. 1926 (Folder 39)
    - Sazonov, A.V. and C.P.R.O.A.S., Apr. 1924-Feb. 1926 (Folder 40)
  - Blukis, P.I. (Folder 41)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Sept. 1922-Apr. 1923
  - Bobrik, P.A.
    - Moravskii,V.I., July 1922-May 1923 (Folder 42)
    - Sazonov, A.V., Aug. 1921-Aug. 1923 (Folder 43)
  - Borisov, M.I.
    - Levchatkin-Atkins, S.V., March 1932 (Folder 44)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Aug. 1931-June 1932 (Folder 45)
  - Burkov, P. (Folder 46)
    - Moravskii, V.I., Feb.-Apr. 1928
  - Burtsev, V.L. (Folder 47)
    - Sazonov, V.A., Feb. 1923-Apr. 1924
  - Cherednichenko-Mersie, V.P. (Folder 48)
    - Moravskii, V.I., July 1925-June 1928
  - Chertkov, G.I.
    - Agapov, E.M., Nov. 1934 (Folder 49)
    - "Avivi," Apr. 1926-Feb. 1927 (Folder 50)
    - Fomin, N.Iu., Jan 1931 (Folder 51)
    - Golovachev, M.P., Nov. 1922-Jan. 1926 (Folder 52)
    - Gondatti, N.I., March 1933 (Folder 53)
    - Kalinin, N.V., June 1932 (Folder 54)
    - KHorvat, D.L., Nov. 1929-June 1935 (Folder 55)
    - Levchatkin-Atkins, K.S., Aug. 1930-June 1935 (Folder 56)
    - Moravskii, V.I.
      - Undated (Folder 57)
      - 1923, Oct.-Dec. (Folder 58)
      - 1924, Jan.-Dec. (Folder 59)
      - 1925, Jan.-Nov. (Box 8, Folder l)
      - 1926, Feb.-Dec. (Folder 2)
      - 1927, Jan.-Dec. (Folder 3)
      - 1928, Jan.-Nov. (Folder 4)
      - 1929, July-Dec. (Folder 5)
      - 1930 Jan.-1931 Dec. (Folder 6)
      - 1932 Feb.-1933 Apr. (Folder 7)
      - 1934 Jan.-1935 Dec. (Folder 8)
    - Popov, G.N., Oct. 1932 (Folder 9)
    - Purin, A.A., Aug. 1929-Feb. 1931 (Folder 10)
    - Sazonov, A.V.
      - 1923, Dec. (Folder 11)
      - 1924, Jan.-Sept. (Folder 12)
      - 1925, Jan.-Nov. (Folder 13)